The last 1-1.5 years are going very bad due to virus.
Millions of people are getting hospitalized.
Many people are not getting treatment.
And the worst thing is that people are not getting treatment due to lack of money.
I have talked many times, many people talk about financial planning.
And we talk about how to invest.
But we forget a very important part of financial planning.
That is health insurance.
So today I will tell you how you should take health insurance.
For whom health insurance is necessary.
And what are the criteria for it.
Some time back I made a video where I talked about financial planning.
And I also talked about investment point of view.
How you can invest.
Which age group should do it, who should do it and who should not.
What are the tax benefits, I talked about all that.
So you can watch that in iButton.
Today I will tell you about medical insurance.
First of all, everyone should take medical insurance.
In financial planning, we say that earning member of the family should take it.
Everyone should take medical insurance.
The child who is born in the house, should get medical insurance at that time.
If it is of less age, then it will be in relatively low rate.
So first of all, I will tell you what is the benefit of medical insurance.
The simple thing is that you have to pay Rs.241 a month.
You will get insurance up to Rs.2 lakh.
If you want more claim, you have to pay Rs.836 a month.
You will get medical insurance up to Rs.1 crore.
Now this is only Rs.250.
The amount of money you eat from outside, like toffee, momos, etc.
You are getting insurance of Rs.2 lakh.
Now do you know how this insurance of Rs.2 lakh is useful?
God forbid, if someone gets injured, then what will happen?
You will suddenly get a requirement for funds.
Now you will say that you have a lot of money.
But taking out Rs.2 lakh altogether or Rs.5 lakh altogether is too much for anyone.
If nothing happens, then it is a good thing.
But you have given only Rs.250 a month lump sum.
And you are safeguard on it.
That if something happens to you, then you will be safe.
Your family will be safe.
Your family member of the house will be safe.
Now I think you must have understood why medical insurance is important for you.
But now I will tell you how you should select medical insurance.
There are many medical insurance in the market.
Which one is right for you?
So let's talk about some terms first.
Which terms are going on in the market these days?
Like there is a feature called automatic restoration of some insurance.
Now basically it is known from the name.
Automatic restoration.
You have taken insurance of Rs.2 lakh. You are giving a monthly case of Rs.241.
You are getting Rs.2 lakh.
Now God forbid, you get hospitalized.
Your Rs.1.5 lakh is spent.
You come back home. You rest.
You have some other problem.
This money will be restored.
You can take the benefit of up to Rs.2 lakh again.
Now there are many such companies in the market.
Which do not give you this restoration.
Now what will be the loss of not giving restoration?
That once Rs.1.5 lakh is gone, you can take a claim of up to Rs.50,000.
If you take more than that, you will have to pay from your pocket.
Again, when we are talking about safeguarding, the whole scene has been removed.
You were taking medical insurance to save yourself.
But you are not able to save yourself because of these things.
Now there is a big confusion going on in the market regarding restoration.
People think that if you have taken insurance of Rs.2 lakh.
And you need Rs.3 lakh.
So first you will get Rs.2 lakh.
After that you will be admitted in the hospital and you can take Rs.2 lakh again.
This will not happen.
When you get discharged, then only it happens.
Or there is a specific tenure.
After that tenure, your restoration happens.
If you have any other problem in between.
For example, someone had a heart attack.
From heart attack, whatever insurance claim he had, he took Rs.1.5 lakh.
Now suddenly he has an accident on the 10th day.
Even then he will get insurance again.
Of Rs.2 lakh.
Regarding heart, the same thing is happening again.
To safeguard this, the company has made rules.
That you will get restored after a specific tenure.
For the same problem.
And that time is not more than 1.5 months.
Next is an important thing.
Accidental injury benefit.
What is accidental injury benefit?
God forbid, you get into an accident.
And if there is an accident, then there is a big expense on a small thing.
And you have taken insurance of Rs.2 lakh.
Let's assume that you want to spend only Rs.250 on these things.
You don't want to go above this.
I told you that there are options up to Rs.800.
You will search in the market.
There are many options.
But let's assume that you want to spend only this much.
You don't earn much.
Or you think that you don't want to spend much.
So you have taken only Rs.2 lakh.
God forbid, if there is an accident.
You have to spend more money.
Then what will you do?
So here I am not telling you to take a big plan.
Here you get a term, Accidental Injury Benefit.
What happens in this?
If there is an accident, then your benefit doubles.
Means if you have taken Rs.2 lakh, then you will get a compensation of Rs.4 lakh.
You will get safeguarding up to Rs.4 lakh.
Which is a very important thing, I personally believe.
So now if you are taking anything, then make sure to check in it.
That accidental injury benefit is getting or not.
Next is a very big problem.
Which I have personally experienced.
Because my brother has also had an operation.
My mother has also been to the hospital many times.
So one big issue is that of cap.
The insurance you get, you have a cap of the room in it.
That you will get this specific room.
You can spend only this much.
There is a lot of drama like this.
And because of that, you get stuck.
Either if that room is not available there.
And you have to upgrade.
Then you put additional money in your pocket.
Again, the reason we are talking about taking medical insurance.
That is completely defied.
What happens many times is that you don't have money there.
You have to move to another hospital.
Again, there is a lot of tension on this thing.
So you also have to see what is the room cap.
What is a good thing?
Companies also give you single occupancy at this time.
Means you can live alone in a room.
You don't get delift rooms.
Means on basic plans.
You get single occupancy in basic plans.
So there is no need to take tension.
And now we have seen that for the last 1-1.5 years.
Everyone is sitting at home.
They don't like to go out.
There are small problems in the house.
For that you have to take consultation.
So for consultation you have to go to the doctor.
Then you have to spend a lot of money.
Nowadays, many companies also give you online doctor consultation.
Okay, means take it online and that is also free.
Unlimited.
Many companies will give.
What will happen to you?
If you have any disease.
And you can also take this family package.
I am clearing this first.
It is not alone.
You can also take the whole family package.
So you have taken the whole family package.
If anyone is getting sick at home.
Take video consultation directly.
And get your treatment.
Along with that,
Is that company giving you medical checkup or not?
Most of the companies give you medical checkup.
Annual one medical checkup is there.
Complete body checkup.
You have to book.
There is a specific center.
Go there.
All your basic tests are done.
It is a good thing.
Next is very important.
Claim settlement ratio.
And what is the mode of the claim?
What is the meaning of mode?
Is it cashless or payment?
Nowadays,
You go.
Admit in the hospital.
You don't have to pay.
Your company will pay them automatically.
Some companies are like this.
In which you have to pay first.
After that, when you are discharged from the hospital.
Then they have to show you the bill.
There is a lot of tension behind that.
And then you get the claim.
So I think go behind cashless.
Don't worry.
If you get a dedicated relationship manager.
Then it is a very good thing.
I personally think so.
So you have to see the claim settlement ratio.
What is the meaning of claim settlement ratio?
How many people are putting requests there?
And how many people are approved?
Higher the better.
More than 95-96% is mandatory.
So now you must be confused.
Which one to take?
So here comes our partner today.
Navi.
I have already made a video on Navi.
In detail.
How Navi was started by Sachin Bansal.
And how he is expanding it.
I have given the video in i button.
You can check it.
The best thing about Navi is.
All the things mentioned above.
All the things are Navi's features.
Navi offers everything.
You get a cashless claim in 20 minutes.
In 20 minutes.
They have a tie-up with more than 10,000 hospitals.
97% is their claim settlement ratio.
All the process is digital.
You don't have to go anywhere.
You are getting a dedicated relationship manager.
More than 12 lakh customers are there.
Who are connected with them.
And the best and most important thing for me.
Is online doctor consultation.
So you get unlimited online doctor consultation.
Free.
Means if there is any problem at home.
You can get help.
Along with that you get an annual medical checkup.
Which you can do once a year.
I am telling you a simple thing.
You just have to pay Rs.241.
And you will save lakhs of rupees.
May god bless you.
So you will be safeguarded.
So for me,
Medical insurance is very important for everyone.
No one has
Surplus money.
And if someone has it.
Then it is a big amount.
To get it in a jiffy.
So I will recommend you to take it.
And based on your requirement.
You can take the plan as per your requirement.
Now you must be thinking about the price.
The price is Rs.241 a month.
And you will get Rs.2 lakhs benefit.
to take medical insurance
take it now
I've given the link in the description
Download the app and take it now
I think
No one can take out money in emergency
0:10:20,600 --> 0:10:02,980
So it's very important
And if they do
They've taken money for some other work
And how can they hide it
I've seen many people
They've messaged me on Instagram
That they're hospitalized
It's a matter of grief
People don't know about medical insurance
241 rupees
I think this amount is not a big amount
You can recharge your mobile
You can talk on the phone
You're getting life saving
And you're being safeguarded
So that you don't face any loss
And if you face an emergency
You don't have to worry about money
I've given the link in the description
Go and take it
Don't delay
I hope you liked the video
Like and share the video
Good morning, good afternoon whenever you're watching this video.